Now earlier, I did mention that the value of one
之前我提到
is actually a bit too high of a good starting weight value.
值 1 是很高的起始权重值
So, choosing weights from a uniform range of values
因此从 0-1 的均匀分布中选择权重
between 0 and 1 is actually not the best range to choose from.
实际上并不是最好的选择范围
You may be wondering how can I select a better range?
那么问题是 如何选择更好的范围？
But we know that for fully connected layers,
我们知道对于全连接层
each node will see every input value,
每个节点会将
multiply it by a model weight and then add the weighted values together.
每个输入值乘以模型权重 然后将加权值相加
In the case of Fashion-MNIST,
对于 Fashion-MNIST
each hidden node in the first layer is seeing 784 input values.
第一个层级中的每个隐藏节点将看到 784 个输入值
The next layer is seeing 256 input values then 128 as input.
第二层将看到 256 个输入值 下一层是 128 个输入值
Because the model weights act as multipliers for all the inputs,
因为模型权重充当所有输入的乘数
it makes sense that the weights should be somehow
因此权重应该与
related to the number of inputs that each node is going to see.
每个节点将看到的输入数量相关
In fact, the relationship is an inverse one.
实际上 这种关系反过来也成立
The more inputs a certain node sees,
某个节点看到的输入越多
the smaller its weight should be.
它的权重就应该越小
So let's see what exact range we should try.
我们看看应该尝试什么范围
A general rule for setting the weights in a neural network
设置神经网络权重的一般法则是
is to set them to be close to zero without being too small.
将它们设为接近 0 但是不能太小
More specifically, we should start with weights and the range of negative -y to y,
初始权重的范围应该是 -y 到 y
where y equals 1 over square root n,
其中 y = 1/√n￣
and n is the number of inputs to a given neuron.
n 表示给定神经元的输入数量
So this rule is basically saying two things: the weights should be centered around zero,
这个法则涉及两个方面：权重应该以 0 为中心
and the range should be quite small and inversely
范围应该很小
related to the number of input nodes for a given layer.
并且与给定层级的输入节点数逆相关
So, let's see if this holds true,
我们看看这个法则是否成立
and let's first create a centered baseline to compare with.
先创建一个居中基准作为比较依据
Let's center our uniform range over zero by
使均匀分布以 0 为中心
shifting it from 0 to 1 to negative five to 0.5.
并将范围从 [0,1] 移到 [-0.5,0.5]
Here, I'm defining a whole new initialization function weights init uniform center.
在这里创建新的初始化函数 weights_init_uniform_center
Then for every linear layer in our network,
对于网络中的每个线性层级
I'm going to initialize the weights of that layer using
我将使用范围为 [-0.5,0.5] 的均匀分布
a uniform distribution with a range of negative to positive 0.5.
初始化该层级的权重
Then I'm creating a new model,
然后创建新的模型 model_centered
model centered, and applying these centered weights to that model.
并将这些居中权重应用到该模型上
Then, I'm gonna do the same thing only for our general rule which uses a value of
然后针对一般法则执行相同的流程
1 over square root n. I'm going to have to
即范围为 1/√n￣
reference the number of inputs to a given layer.
我需要引用给定层级的输入数量
So, here I've prepared an initialization function,
在这里创建初始化函数
and I'm looking at every linear layer.
查看每个线性层级
Now we just have to define y. I can get the number of input features from
现在只需定义 y我可以通过调用 m.in_features
a specific layer by calling m.in_features and I'm storing that as a variable n. Then,
获取特定层级的输入特征数量并将其存储在变量 n 中
I'm calculating y as 1 over the square root of n. Finally,
然后计算 y = 1/√n￣
I'm initializing the weights of each linear layer with
最后使用以值 y 居中的均匀分布
a uniform distribution that's centered around this value, y.
初始化每个线性层级的权重
Then, I'm creating another new model and applying these initial weights to it.
然后创建另一个新模型并应用这些初始权重
Finally, I'm going to compare the behavior of these two models,
最后比较这两个模型的行为
model centered and model rule.
它们是 model_centered 和 model_rule
I'm giving each a descriptive name and use
分别设定了一个描述性的名称
a my compare_int_weights function to see their behavior over time.
使用 compare_int_weights 函数查看它们的行为
So first off, we can see on the y-axis that
首先 在 y 轴上可以看出
our lost values are orders of magnitude smaller than what we've seen previously.
损失值比之前见到的损失值小了几个数量级
This behavior is really promising.
这种行为让人信心大增
Not only is the lost decreasing for both of these models,
不仅两个模型的损失降低了
but it seems to do so very quickly for a uniform weights that follow the general rule.
而且遵守一般法则的均匀权重损失似乎下降很快
After only two epochs,
仅在两个周期之后
we get a fairly high validation accuracy.
就获得了比较高的验证准确率
Almost 86% for using our general rule.
使用一般法则几乎达到 86%
This should start to give you some intuition for why starting out with
现在你应该明白为何设置正确的初始权重
the right initial weights can really help your training process.
对训练流程很有帮助了
Now, there's really one more kind of
在结束之前
distribution that I want to take a look at before we wrap up.
还有一种分布需要介绍
Since the uniform distribution has the same chance of picking any value and arrange,
因为均匀分布从某个范围中选择任何值的概率是一样的
what if we used a distribution that had
如果我们选择一种分布
a higher chance of picking numbers closer to zero?
它能以更高的概率挑选接近 0 的数字 会怎样？
This is the normal distribution which we'll look at next.
下面我们将研究正态分布